안녕하세요?
- 어서 오세요
- 네, 안녕하세요
전 피비 부페이인데
지금 아기가 나와요
I'm Phoebe Buffay, and I have
babies coming out.
그렇군요, 진통이 시작됐나요?
Have you started having contractions?
아직, 많이 아프다던데
진짜 아픈가요?
Not yet. I heard they really hurt.
Do they?
- 그게...
- 엄마야
Oh, my God!
괜찮아
어느 분이 아기 아빠 되시죠?
Which of you is the father?
여긴 아빠가 없고
아빠는 제 남동생이에요
None of them are.
The father is my brother.
알겠습니다
I'll miss watching you
freak people out like that.
너 사람들 겁주는 덴
뭐 있다니깐
좋아, 피비...
여길 봐
This is for the babies
to look at someday.
나중에 애들이 볼 거니까
시작하기 전에 한마디 해
Do you want to say anything
before it starts?
그래...
Hi, kids! It's me, Aunt Phoebe.
안녕, 얘들아
나야, 피비
Can't wait to see you.
Please don't hurt me!
너희들 보고 싶다
나 아프게 하지 마
What took you so long?
왜 이렇게 늦었어
택시는 같이 출발했는데
Your cab left when ours did.
내가 재킷을 놓고 와서
또 들어갔지 뭐야
We went back because
I forgot my jacket.
You're not wearing one.
재킷 안 입었잖아
Oh, man!
I did it again!
젠장! 또야?
저기, 누가 동생네한테
연락 좀 해줘, 엄마는...
Someone has to call
Frank and Alice.
My mom might
What are you doing?
조이, 뭐해
I've got to get the "before" shot!
미리 찍어둬야지
The One Hundredth
베스 이스라엘 의료센터
We spoke to the nurse.
The reason your doctor is late...
피비, 간호사랑 얘기했는데
왜 담당의가 안 오냐니까
...is because she's not coming.
- 출근을 못했다는 거야
- 뭐?
샤워하다 머리가 깨졌대
She hit her head in the shower.
Oh, my God. She's so stupid!
환장하겠네, 바보 아냐?
Phoebe, it's gonna be okay.
피비, 괜찮을 거야
네 아랫도리로 빠지는 게
아니니까 말은 쉽게 나오지
I don't see three kids
coming out of your vagina!
Listen. The nurse said
the doctor is wonderful.
저기, 간호사가 그러는데
실력 있는 의사가 봐준대
He's head of the department.
그래, 산부인과 과장이래
All right. Oh, dear God, save me!
- 이런, 엄마야
- 왜?
I'm having my first contraction!
첫 번째 진통이야
Oh, it's not bad.
- 견딜 만한데?
- 좋아
And so the miracle of birth begins.
And l
이리하야 탄생의 기적이
시작되도다
You okay?
괜찮냐?
Something hurts.
여기가 아픈데
동정 통증이야
너무 고맙다 얘
It's sympathy pains.
That's so sweet!
I didn't know I cared that much.
내가 그렇게 신경을 썼나?
- 반갑습니다
- 안녕하세요
I'm Dr. Harad.
I'll be delivering your babies.
피비, 해러드 박사예요
제가 출산을 도울 겁니다
You'll be in good hands.
I've been doing this a long time.
걱정하지 마세요
전 경험이 많으니까
잠시 후에 시작하겠어요
긴장할 거 없어요
I'll be back to do your internal.
Just relax, everything looks great.
모두 정상이니까
그리고 전 '폰지'를 좋아합니다
And also, I love Fonzie.
Did he just say he loves Fonzie?
방금 폰지를 좋아한다고 했나?
That's what it sounded like.
나도 그렇게 들었어
All right.
그렇구만
Am I late?
Nobody came out yet, right?
내가 늦은 건 아니지?
아무도 안 나왔어?
No, we haven't started yet.
Where's Alice?
그래, 시작 안 했어
앨리스는?
Delaware. Until she gets here,
I'll be your coach.
델라웨어에서 오는 길이야
그때까지는 내가 코치할게
Don't worry. She told me
about the LaMazda stuff.
걱정 마, 엘리스한테
라마즈다 얘긴 다 들었어
If you get the babies out
by month's end...
월말까지 애를 나오게 해야
2% 재정지원을 받을 수 있어
...you get two percent financing.
그래요
Monica, you're gonna be
very proud of me.
모니카, 나 장한 일했다
I just got us dates with two
unbelievably cute nurses.
숨 막히게 귀여운 간호사
두 명을 확보해뒀어
Oh, my!
저런...
They're male nurses.
남자 간호사들이야
Not in my head.
그 생각은 못했다
They want to take us out
Saturday night! What do you say?
어쨌든 토요일 밤에
만나자고 하는데, 어때?
I don't think so.
- 내키지 않는다
- 뭐? 무슨 소리야
What are you talking about?
You've been telling me
to get over Ross and move on.
로스를 잊고 갈 길을
가라던 게 누군데
I'm moving on and so are you.
내가 가면 너도 가야지
대체 왜 못 간다는 거야?
Why don't you want to go?
Why don't you give me
a good reason...
네가 이유를 말하면
내가 판단해줄게
...and I'll tell you if it's true.
-What?
-Harder than it sounds, isn't it?
- 뭐?
- 말하려니 힘들겠지?
You're coming.
And when they get off...
가는 걸로 알게
퇴근하면 카페테리아에서
젤로 먹기로 했어
...we'll go get some Jello with them.
그래, 젤로는 늘 먹을 수 있지
There's always room for Jello.
How do you make that dirty?
참 불결하게 만든다
쉬워, 뭐든 가능하다고
한번 볼래?
It's easy.
I can do it with anything.
Grandma's chicken salad....
할머니의 치킨샐러드
로스
Get a shot of this.
이걸 찍어
아기들아, 너희들이
태어난 날의 헤드라인이야
These are the headlines
when you were born.
Now, girl baby, turn away.
And boy babies...
여자아이들은 눈 돌리고
남자아이들은...
...check it out!
보시라
This is what naked women
looked like when you were born.
너희들이 태어난 달의
알몸 여성들이란다
Now let's dive into the good stuff.
이제 좋은 거 보러 가자
Okay, I'm having another one!
이런, 또 온다
This one doesn't hurt eith
Yes, it does!
이번에도 안 아픈데...
아니, 아프다
I was kind of hoping that was it.
이걸로 끝났으면 했는데
Where are Monica and Rachel, anyway?
모니카랑 레이첼은 어디 갔어?
A couple of nurses asked them out.
간호사들 만난다는데
같이 있겠지
Really? Male nurses?
- 그래? 남자 간호사?
- 나도 대따 실망이야
Yeah, I was bummed too.
So they're going on dates.
데이트한대? 언제?
-When?
-I think Saturday.
토요일일 거야
-What's with him?
-Sympathy pains.
왜 저래?
동정 통증이라고
It was sweet at first, but now I think
he's trying to steal my thunder.
처음엔 고마웠는데 이제 보니
내 전공을 가로채려는 거야
- 괜찮죠?
- 네
Let's see what we got here.
어디 봅시다
Oh, you know, Fonzie dated triplets.
알아요? 폰지도 세쌍둥이랑
데이트했는데
This Fonzie person
you keep referring to...
계속 말씀하시는
그 폰지라는 분이
...is that another doctor?
- 다른 의사신가요?
- 아뇨
Oh, no, no.
폰지는 아서 폰저렐리의
별명이에요
Fonzie is the nickname
of Arthur Fonzerelli.
The Fonz.
폰지
All right.
알았습니다
실례할게요
It's not that weird, is it?
그렇게 이상하진 않잖아?
It's very weird!
엄청 이상해
누가 날 헤벌레 임신녀라고
하는 거 싫어
I don't want some guy down there
telling me I'm "dilated-a-mundo."
He doesn't seem to be
impersonating Fonzie
내가 볼 땐 저 의사가
폰지를 사칭하는 건...
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거야!
Why are you defending him?
Just get me another doctor...
왜 저 사람을 두둔해?
다른 의사 데려와
제정신에 폰지도 아닌 사람
...who isn't crazy
and doesn't Fonzie!
Again, it's not
다시 말하지만...
여기 있었구나
Hey, there you are!
There's something you should know.
할 얘기가 있어
너 간호사랑
데이트한다는 거?
Is this about you dating the nurse?
Joey told me.
그래, 조이한테 들었어
난 아무렇지도 않아
I am so fine. You and l,
we're just nothing.
너하고 난 그냥...
즐긴 거니까 뭐
Just goofing around.
I was about to tell you
I was getting out of it.
사실 난 안 만나겠다는
말을 하려고 했는데
But if we're just "goofing around,"
maybe I will go out with him.
그냥 즐긴 거라니까
만나도 괜찮겠다
Fine. Maybe I will too.
좋아, 나도 만날 거야
Hey! Look what I found
in the gift shop.
얘들아, 내가 뭘 샀나... 봐
Get up! Get up! Get up!
빨랑 일어나세요
- 좋아, 피비?
- 그래
This is Dr. Oberman.
오버맨 박사님이셔
He has no strong feelings
about Fonzie...
폰지를 좋아하지도 않고
...or any of the Happy Days gang.
'해피 데이스' 출연진에겐
관심조차 없어
You're going into what grade?
안녕, 이제 몇 학년 올라가니?
I'm actually a first-year resident.
I graduated early.
레지던트 1년차지만 그런 말
많이 듣죠, 벌써 졸업했어요
나도, 로스?
Me too.
I should have specified
I'd need a grown-up doctor.
어른 의사라고 말할 걸 그랬나?
Really, I'm fully qualified
저도 자격이 충분...
Doogie!
시끄러워, 얘
Doesn't anybody understand that
I'm going to be having babies soon?
곧 애 나오는 거 몰라서 이래?
Go, little boy! Go!
가! 가라니까, 이 녀석아!
Oh, cool. You made him cry!
누나가 쟤를 울렸네
Mr. Tribbiani, I'm afraid
you've got kidney stones.
트리비아니 씨?
선생님은 신장결석입니다
Well, what else could it be?
다른 가능성은 없나요?
It's kidney stones.
신장결석이에요
Or....
또는...
Kidney stones.
신장결석이지요
- 다른 걸 수도 있잖아요
- 그럼 신장결석이지요
-lf it was something else?
-Well, that would be "kidney stones."
You're getting there.
다 돼갑니다
정말 운이 좋은 아이들이에요
These babies are very, very lucky.
They are? Why?
그래요? 왜죠?
They'll be born
on the Fonz's half-birthday.
폰지의 생일이 딱
6개월 남았거든요
Happy Birthday.
생일 축하드려요
Just to clarify...
확실히 해두겠는데
전 폰지가 아니에요
...I'm not Fonzie.
It's a terrific thing that you're having
these babies for Frank and Alice.
동생 부부한테 참
좋은 일을 하는 거야
No, it is.
- 그러게
- 그럼
Can I tell you a secret?
- 비밀 하나 말해 줘?
- 그래
I want to keep one.
내가 하나 키울래
나 뉴스에 나오겠네
Oh, I'm gonna be on the news.
You must be kidding.
피비, 그거 농담이겠지?
안 되는 거 잘 알잖아
You know you can't keep
one of these babies.
Maybe I can. You don't know.
왜, 네가 어떻게 알아
내가 왜 몰라, 동생 부부는
아이들을 모두 원할 거야
I do. Frank and Alice will
want to keep all their children.
Maybe not. You know?
아닐 수도 있지, 안 그래?
셋은 너무 많아
Three babies are a handful.
- 하나쯤은 치우고 싶을 걸
- 맙소사!
Maybe they'll want to unload one.
I hate to miss an opportunity
because I didn't ask.
물어보지도 않고
포기할 순 없어
Phoebe, no.
This is insane.
피비, 이건 미친 짓이야
- 물어봐
- 뭐?
Just ask him.
What? Me?
내가?
그럼 내가 물어보리?
경우에 맞는 얘기야?
I can't ask him!
Do you know how inappropriate
that would be?
프랭크랑 얘기해보라니까
그럼 걔 생각을...
All I'm saying is,
just talk to Frank.
Just feel him out.
됐어, 어떻게 프랭크한테
애 하나를 포기하라고 해
No. I will not ask Frank
to give you one of his kids.
맞아
You're right.
네가 키운다고 해
Tell him it's for you.
Feeling better, sweetie?
기분 좀 나아졌니?
Maybe a little.
약간
Wish you hadn't seen me throw up.
토하는 꼴까지 볼 건 뭐야
Me too.
나도 후회돼
얘들아, 방금 들었는데
어떻게 된 거야?
I just heard. What's up?
Kidney stones!
신장결석입니다
Ordinarily, we try to break
the stones up with shock waves.
보통 이런 경우엔
충격파로 결석을 부수지만
방광에 너무 가까이 있어서
But they're too close to the bladder.
배출되기를 기다리거나
아니면 요도로 올라가서...
Either we wait for you to pass them
or else go up the urethra
No, no, no, no.
Nothing is going up, okay?
안될 말이죠
올라가는 건 안 돼요
Up is not an option.
What's a urethra?
올라가는 건 제외하세요
근데 요도가 뭡니까?
Are you crazy?
미쳤어요?
Did you ask him?
물어봤어?
No, I haven't had a chance yet.
아니, 단둘이 있을
기회가 없었어
I'm kind of on a clock here.
나 얼마 안 남았어
Oh, Fonzie.
폰지...
You know who I always liked?
Mork.
제가 좋아한 건 모크였어요
Undo it. Undo it.
빨랑 취소해, 빨랑
Fonzie met Mork.
폰지가 모크를 만났고
모크는 폰지를 얼려버렸죠
Mork froze Fonzie.
네...
네, 하지만...
폰지는 원래 쿨 해서
But Fonzie was already cool.
So he wasn't hurt. Right?
아무렇지도 않았어요, 맞죠?
Yeah, that's right.
네, 맞아요
How you doing?
피비
- 어서 와
- 좀 어때?
Okay. Doctor says any minute now.
이제 얼마 안 남았대
You know, Alice is going
to be here so soon.
저기, 앨리스가 곧 도착할 건데
부탁 하나만 들어줬으면 해서...
You couldn't just do me a favor
and, like, hold them in?
내가 받아도 될까?
Sorry, I'm in the middle of
the last favor you asked me to do.
미안한데 지금 네 마지막
부탁을 들어주고 있단다
여기 있었군요
- 어서 와요
- 레이첼
This is Dan, one of the guys
we're dating on Saturday.
모니카, 이쪽은 댄이야
토요일에 만나기로 한 분
- 댄, 모니카예요
- 반갑습니다
Nice to meet you.
안녕, 댄?
I'm really looking forward
to Saturday night. Really!
토요일이 정말 기대돼요
정말! 정말!
So, Dan...
댄, 의사가 아닌 간호사라...
...nurse, not a doctor, huh?
Kind of girlie, isn't it?
좀 여성스럽죠?
챈들러
That's okay. I'm doing this
to get through medical school.
괜찮아요, 전 의대생인데
학자금 마련 차 하는 일이죠
걸프전에서 일할 땐
여성스럽지 않더군요
And it didn't feel "girlie"
during the Gulf War.
Sure.
그렇죠
Thanks for doing that for us,
by the way.
국가를 위해 좋은 일을 했군요
주말까지 기다릴 거 있나요?
내일은 시간 나세요?
Why wait till Saturday?
Are you free tomorrow?
Sure.
I'll get somebody to cover me.
그럼요, 근무시간을 바꾸죠 뭐
Great!
잘됐다
Hey, you and me, Saturday night?
나랑 토요일 밤에 어때요?
- 싫어요
- 네, 좋습니다
-No.
-All right, very good!
This is a big one.
이건 심각한데
Get these things out of me!
이것 좀 꺼내 줘
Breathe! Breathe through the pain.
심호흡, 심호흡...
고통 속의 심호흡
I want the drugs, Ross!
약을 줘, 로스!
약을 달라니까!
I do too! I do too!
나도! 나도!
Yeah, I love you.
Okay, bye.
저도 사랑해요
안녕히 계세요
- 왔어요?
- 네
That was Alice's mom.
Alice left five hours ago.
장모님 말로는 다섯 시간 전에
출발했다는데 왜 안 올까요?
She should be here.
She'll make it on time.
걱정 말아요
곧 도착하겠죠
- 네
- 그래요
저기, 프랭크...
So, Frank...
...three babies.
That just seems like a lot, huh?
아기가 셋이면
너무 많지 않아요?
나한텐 아니죠
Not to me.
Fair enough.
알아들었어요
You're at ten centimeters.
Time to start having babies.
좋아요, 10센티미터예요
기다리던 순간이 왔군요
아기 아빠만 남아주세요
I want only the father here.
- 사랑해
- 그래, 기운 내
-We love you.
-Good luck.
- 잘될 거야
- 사랑해
- 안녕, 댄
- 잘 가요, 모니카
간다, 바부야
좋아, 클램프와 살균타월
그리고 채널 31
I need a clamp, a sterile towel
and Channel 31.
그게 뭐죠?
What is that?
엄마야!
Oh, my God!
아뇨, 재미있는 거예요
폰지가 봉고를 연주하죠
Oh, no, no! It's a good one.
Fonzie plays the bongos.
좋아요, 준비됐죠?
이제 힘주세요
Ready? Time to try pushing.
준비됐죠?
소변 좀 봅시다
Ready? Time to try peeing.
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
It's almost time to try peeing.
잠깐 대기!
이게 들어가면 합시다
힘줘요, 잘하고 있어요
정신을 집중하고 힘주세요
Push. Concentrate on pushing.
네, 그렇죠
머리가 보여요
I see the head.
Yes, it has a head!
- 그래! 머리는 달렸어!
- 좋아요
계속 힘줘요, 자!
Keep pushing. Come on.
I can't believe somebody's coming out!
누나 몸에서 사람이 나오다니
사람이 나와
There's somebody coming out of you!
- 내 아들이야
- 됐어요
-It's my son!
-All right.
Here's your first baby!
첫 아기입니다
아싸!
Yes! We got a baby boy!
아들이 나왔어요!
Frank Junior, Junior!
프랭크 주니어 주니어!
How does he look?
어떻게 생겼어요?
엄청난 흉물단지예요!
So gross!
Okay. You ready to push again?
자, 다시 힘줘볼까요?
I already had a baby.
Leave me alone!
하나 낳았잖아요
건드리지 말아요
Come on, you can do it!
You can do it!
자, 힘내라고
누나는 할 수 있어
아싸!
꼬마 레슬리가 나왔어요!
Little Leslie's here!
We got another one!
Oh, my God! I can't believe
I have two children.
맙소사, 애가 벌써
둘이나 생기다니
How scary is that?
살 떨리네
Come on, little Chandler,
it's time to be born.
나와라, 꼬마 챈들러
어서 나와야지, 뭐하니...
네, 좋아요
자, 나오고 있어요
He's coming!
Yes, he's coming!
Hey, where's his thing?
그거 어디 갔죠?
Chandler's a girl!
챈들러가 여자예요!
Oh, God! Kindergarten flashback.
이런, 유치원 때 생각나네
They read the sonogram wrong,
because they thought it was a boy.
초음파를 잘못 읽었는지
사내앤 줄만 알았는데...
But Chandler's a girl!
챈들러는 여자예요, 여자!
그래, 계속 소리 질러
Okay, keep saying it.
-Am I too late?
-No, no. Everything's okay.
내가 너무 늦었나요?
괜찮아, 모두 건강해
손가락 발가락도 다 있고
There's 30 fingers and 30 toes.
We have our babies?
- 우리한테 아이가 생겼어요?
- 그래
We have our babies.
- 아이가 생기다니
- 그렇다니까
Oh, my God!
- 죽겠네...
- 해낸 거야
You did it, man.
Would you like to see them?
한번 보겠어요?
They're so small.
참 쬐끄맣다
- 내일 전화하죠
- 그래요
-I'll call you tomorrow.
-Great.
Are you really going to date
that nurse man?
그 남자 간호사랑
진짜 만날 거야?
You and I are just
"goofing around."
너랑도 즐겼는데
딴 남자랑 못 즐길 건 뭐야
I thought, why not
"goof around" with him?
I don't know if you've looked up
"goofing around" in the dictionary.
넌 '즐긴다'는 용어의 뜻을
사전에서 봤는지 모르지만
Well, I have...
내가 찾아봤는데 정확한
단어의 정의가 뭐냐하면
...and the technical definition is:
Two friends who care a lot
about each other...
서로를 많이 좋아하는
두 사람의 친구가
...and have amazing sex...
엄청난 섹스를 하고
...and just want to spend
more time together.
함께 시간을
보내고 싶어하는 것
But if you have this new
dictionary that gets you mad at me...
최신사전을 보고
화를 내는 거라면
내 원본사전을
보여줄 수도 있어
...then we have to get you
my original one.
I am so bad at this.
나 참 재주 없지?
-You're better than you think you are.
-Really?
- 그렇게 형편없진 않아
- 정말?
좋아, 그럼...
Okay. So if?
- 그만둘 때만 알면
- 지금 그만두려고 했거든
-Know when to stop.
-I sensed that I should stop.
So we're okay?
- 우리 괜찮은 거지?
- 그래
I'm gonna go tell Dan that
it's not gonna happen.
댄한테 가서 약속 취소할게
-Don't do the dance.
-Right.
- 춤추지 마
- 알았어
You're my favorite.
네가 제일 예쁘다
-Which one do you have?
-I don't care.
- 어떤 애를 갖고 싶은데?
- 상관없어
얘들아
어서 와
Frank and Alice want me to tell you
they're making phone calls.
프랭크랑 앨리스는
아직 전화하고 있어
Did you talk to them
about, you know....
그 얘기는 꺼내봤니?
그래
No, honey.
아니, 못했어
알았어
It was a long shot.
힘든 일이지
You guys? Can I just have
a second alone with the babies?
얘들아, 잠깐 아기들하고만
있었으면 좋겠는데
- 그래
- 그렇게 해
So here you are.
이렇게 만났구나
페트리 접시에 든 너희들과
얘기한 게 엊그제 같은데
Seems like yesterday I was talking
to you in that petri dish.
Everyone said labor was
the hardest thing.
다들 출산이 가장 힘들다지만
그건 틀린 말이야
But they were wrong. This is.
Well, I had the most fun
with you guys.
함께 있어서 정말 즐거웠어
I wish I could take you home
and see you every day.
집에 데려가서 매일 보고 싶지만
I'll settle for being
your favorite aunt.
좋은 고모가 되는 걸로 만족할게
I know Alice's sister has a pool,
but you lived in me.
너희들 이모 집엔 수영장이
있지만 너흰 내 몸에서 살았어
Okay, so we're cool.
그래, 괜찮아
We're gonna be great.
우린 잘 지낼 거야
Little high-fives.
하이파이브 할까?
Well, if you're going to cry....
너희까지 울면 어떡해?
Phoebe, we are so proud of you.
You're amazing!
너 정말 장하다
큰일 해냈어
I know.
나도 알아
정말 그렇게 아픈 거야?
Does it hurt as bad as they say?
그래, 넌 못 참아
You won't be able to take it.
꼬마 챈들러는 여자 앤데
이름을 뭐라고 지을래?
Now that little Chandler is a girl,
what'll they name her?
They'll call her Chandler.
챈들러라고 부를 거야
Kind of a masculine name,
don't you think?
그건 좀 남성스럽지 않아?
It works on you.
너한텐 맞잖아
좀더 여성스럽게 바꿔봐
챈들러렛처럼
Maybe they can girlie it up a bit,
like Chandlerette.
앨리스는 이러던데
채니 패니
Alice called her Channy-fanny.
Ha-ha, Channy-fanny.
아하, 채니 패니